Guide to the American Association of University Women. Durham Branch (N.C.) Records, 1913-1976 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
American Association of University Women. Durham Branch (N.C.) records 1913-1976 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
American Association of University Women. Durham Branch (N.C.)
4.5 Linear Feet Appoximately 4500 Items
The Durham, N.C. branch of the American Association of University Women was founded in 1913.
The records of the AAUW Durham chapter span the years from its founding in 1913 through the 1960s. The central organizational records are almost complete for this period, including minutes of Executive Board meetings, Presidents' files, financial records, membership information, and national and state convention files. The Presidents' files contain chiefly correspondence, but programs, membership rosters, and leadership information are also present. Records are arranged alphabetically by file groups.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The American Association of University Women. Durham Branch (N.C.) Records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1967 and 1977.
Historical Note
The Durham, N.C. branch of the American Association of University Women was founded in 1913.
Collection Overview
The Association of Collegiate Alumnae formed in 1881; the Southern Association of College Women formed in 1903. They merged in 1921 to become the American Association of University Women. The Durham branch was founded in 1913 and became part of the AAUW at its founding in 1921. The records of the AAUW Durham chapter span the years from its founding in 1913 through the 1960s. The central organizational records are almost complete for this period, including minutes of Executive Board meetings, Presidents' files, financial records, membership information, and national and state convention files. The Presidents' files contain chiefly correspondence, but programs, membership rosters, and leadership information are also present. Records are arranged alphabetically by file groups.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
American Association of University Women. Durham Branch (N.C.)
College alumnae
Durham, N.C.--Higher education
Education -- Societies, etc
North Carolina -- Higher education
Women -- Education (Higher).
Contents of Collection
- Association of University Women. Durham Branch (N.C.) Records, 1913-1976 and undated, (11 boxes)
  - Unorganized records: history of Durham branch, constitution, by-laws, minutes, newsletters, budget information, some undated (Box 1-2)
  - Duplicates (by-laws and other documents) (Box 3)
  - Minutes of Executive Board meetings, 1929-1962 (Box 4)
  - Minutes of Executive Board meetings, 1965-1967 (Box 5)
  - National conventions files, 1947, 1957, 1961
  - President's files, 1931-1949
  - President's files, 1950-1962 (Box 6)
  - President's files, 1962-1969 (Box 7)
  - Regional conferences
  - Minutes and roll book
  - State conventions, 1942-1964; Durham convention, 1962 (Box 8)
  - Treasurer's records, 1932-1958
  - Treasurer's records, 1960s (Box 9)
  - By-laws
  - Yearbooks, 1967-1968, 1968-1969
  - Oversize materials (Box 10-11)
- Addition (1977), 1958-1976, (3 boxes, 3.0 linear feet)
  Files contain meeting minutes (1966-1973); notes on the history of the Durham branch; subject files on education, international relations, other branches of the AAUW; bylaws, membership, and fellowship information; a handbook for AAUW leadership; and financial records.
  - Addition (Box 12-14)